The credit for today's video goes to
this comment of Mr. Niranjan. Sir,
thank you for your comment. If you all
want to understand the details of Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance Company Limited's Secure Plus Plan, check the description of today's video.
You will get the
link of the Secure Plus Plan video. Along with
this, you can tell us in the comment section
which plan you want the next video to be
related to because every video on the channel
comes according to your questions, suggestions and comments. Therefore, to stay
connected with us, subscribe to the channel and turn on
all notification bells
and do not forget to like and share the video.
Hello everyone, a very warm welcome to
all of you. You are watching You The Real. I am
your own personal advisor Amitraj Sharma.
In today's video, we will understand the details of Aditya Birla Sun Life
Insurance Company Limited's Vision Life
Secure Plan. So let us
know the details of the plan. In simple words,
this plan is a whole life endowment plan, which
means that your life cover will be
for your whole life and beyond the premium you
pay to the insurance company,
you will not have any kind of market related
risk like equity.  Or, just like it happens in stocks,
every year at the end of the financial year, the company will announce a bonus,
which will be paid to you as maturity along with the
maturity benefit. If the
company announces it, then during the policy term,
your life cover will remain; if
something happens to you, the death benefit will be given to the nominee.
However, if you have
taken the maturity benefit and die after that, the
death benefit will still be given to the nominee. We will
understand how later. For now,
turn the video on full screen so that
you can understand the eligibility criteria of Aditya Bedla Sunla Life
Insurance Company Limited's Vision Life
Secure Plan.
This plan
is available for everyone from minors to senior citizens
because its entry age limit is from 30
days to 60 years. The
policy term in the plan is at least 15 years and the
maximum can be up to 35 years. If
you take this plan for a minor, then the policy
term will have to be such that he/she turns 18 years old
because  The minimum entry age limit
is 18 years and if you take a plan for yourself, then the
maximum policy term you
can take is that you become 75 years old while remaining under the plan
because the maximum
maturity age limit is 75 years. The
premium payment term is regular pay, that is,
you will have to pay the premium continuously for as many years as the policy term. The minimum
sum assured limit in the plan has been kept at ₹1 lakh
and the annual base premium
you have to pay, whose minimum limit is
₹1, is available. All the modes of premium available are
yearly, half-yearly, quarterly,
monthly. If you want to pay the premium, then for that
you will have to choose the NEC option in
which the premium will be auto-debited from your bank account. There are
mainly two benefits in this plan. The first is the death
benefit. If death occurs during the policy term, then
what will be the death benefit? First, let us
understand the death benefit. The plan
tells us that along with the sum assured on death, there is a
regular bonus which you
can call simple reversionary bonus. Along with that, if  The company has
announced a terminal bonus at the time of
death, so it is definitely given.
When does the nominee get this benefit? In the form of death benefit,
when there is a death during the policy term.
And to know the sum assured on death,
you compare the base sum assured that you take while taking the plan.
You
withdraw 10 times the annual premium.
As soon as the policy term is completed,
you get the maturity benefit.
At maturity, the sum assured that
you choose while taking the plan, along with the
regular bonus and terminal bonus, if
announced by the company, will be paid to
you. After you have taken the maturity benefit,
you will remain under the cover of the plan till the age of 100 years.
And
even after taking the maturity benefit,
you do not have to pay any premium for the life cover,
as is the case with LIC's Jeevan Anand
plan, in the same manner and
you must have also seen the video, a few days ago,
we made that video related to that plan,
so Aditya Billa is from
Vision Life of Sunlife Insurance.
To understand the benefits of Secure Plan, let us take an
example here. Let us assume that Mr. A is
35 years old and is
taking a policy term of 25 years. That means
he will pay premium for 25 years only. If
he has taken a sum assured
of ₹1 lakh, then he will pay premium of ₹70 annually.
Suppose Mr. A has completed the 25 years, then the
maturity benefit will be credited. The
bonus rate mentioned to us on
their website is ₹100 per sum of ₹1, that is,
4.3% of your sum assured. So, to
calculate the average regular bonus here, what will you do? If you
calculate 4.3% of 5 lakh and
multiply it by 25, then the average regular
bonus amount will be ₹37500. The positive term of 25 years is ₹10000.
Therefore, if you multiply it by 25,
what will Mr. A get as maturity benefit?  You will get a
sum assured of Rs. 1 lakh along with a
cured regular bonus of Rs. 37500 and a terminal
bonus. The policy term has been
completed here, but for
how long will he remain covered? At the time of maturity,
Mr. Ek's age will be 60 years,
so the life cover period
after maturity will be 40 years
because he will remain under cover till the age of 100. If
he turns 60, then
subtract 60 from 100 and it will come to 40. It says
that the minimum death benefit will be
105% of the total premium paid.
You will find it written in the policy brochure, so if you pay a
premium of Rs. 46750 in 25 years, if
you take out 105% of it, the
amount will be 987.50 paise. Right, so it is said
that the minimum death benefit will be this much only.
Okay, in the plan, but now the
question arises that at the time of maturity  After taking the benefit,
if death occurs then what will be the
minimum cover? In such a case the sum assured
on death will be ₹1 lakh
because it will be equal to the sum assured, that is the
sum assured will be the life cover in future. Let me
repeat again the sum assured will be the life cover after
maturity.
Now suppose Mr. A dies
within 10 years of the policy, then in such a case the
sum assured on death will be ₹155000, that
is fine and the sum assured on death will be ₹1 lakh
because if we take out 10 times the annual premium then it will be
less than 5 lakhs. In such a case the
nominee of Mr. A will get 5 lakhs as sum assured on death
and
₹155000 as regular bonus and
if the company announces the terminal bonus then
that will also be available and see only the
company can tell about the terminal bonus. Now if
death occurs during the policy term then the amount of death benefit will be available.  The
policy will be discontinued after that. Okay, the
bonus information is on your screen, you
get this information on the website itself.
You are seeing here that we had
taken a positive term of 25 years, so
what do we get above ₹000? We get a regular bonus,
which we can also call a simple reversionary bonus.
2000 in March 2022 as well as
in 2023. Now you will know about this
after April. If you want information about this bonus, then
you can check it directly yourself from the reference section of the description of the link video.
You get six different riders in the plan,
whose names are on your screen. You can
pause and read it. If you
want to know about these riders, then
write the name of the rider in the comment section. We will
bring you a video in detail. Okay,
now see, the plan is life insurance, so
understand the grace period. If
you have not taken the monthly mode of premium, then you will
get a grace period of 30 days. If you have taken the monthly mode of
premium, then you will get a grace period of 15 days.
That is the extra time
when your premium due date is over
then you get extra time
right you will get a free look up period of
15 days if you have
taken the plan directly from the insurance company, if not then it is 30
days this is the time period if
you feel that the plan was given to you
with wrong information then during this time
you can cancel the plan and take a refund of the
after tax amount
you will get tax benefit whatever premium you pay will
get direction under 80c the
maturity benefit will be
available under 1010d right and after maturity the other
benefits are available
under 8d you know if you
add a rider then you get the benefit of that too
under d right
thank you very much for watching the video till the end understand one thing
yourself and make others understand that
insurance is a protection
never take incomplete protection if the information is clear
then please like and share the video stay
connected with us by subscribing to our channel
Also, in the comment section, please tell us about
which plan you want the next video to be related to
and no matter how good the plan seems, no matter
which company it is from,
do not buy the plan without reading the policy document.